so you've been
saying um many
times that the
problem is that we are affected in the
first place in other words we
place in other words we
are we anger is possible lust is
possible we get we can get confused
suffering is possible suffering is
possible for us H could
H could
you so so the goal really is to not be
affected in the first place not to do
something unac accounted yeah well the
like uh that's the kind of fundamental
difference that I often try to highlight
is dhama the practice of dhama is not
supposed to just help help you with
things help you with things that bother
you help you deal with them it's
basically supposed to appro your
liability to it to things that bother
you so it doesn't manage your suffering
it removes possibility for you to suffer
in the first
place so you and that that's when that
say a personal goal for your practice it
should be I don't want to be affected by things
be I don't want to be affected by things
to begin with not I want to have a
perfect management technique that will
always help me deal with whatever
suffering have Arison see that's the
problem already suffering has aason you
might be very skilled in dealing with it
but you're not skilled in not having it
arise in the first place and that's what
should be your issue so that's why even
you know the Buddha would often describe
like his teaching uh that frees you from
suffering brings sensation of
being the the the ending of
Bava the ending of of these things
becoming for you manifesting enduring
that you have to manage them then later
means they're not anymore being has
ceased they're
gone so that is the goal of the dhama
sensation of being not management of
things that are for you here and
now sensation
of suffering suffering s greed diversion delusion
delusion
so I can get angry I can get angry but
then I can find out
a some sort of technique to manage my
anger yeah oh when you get angry think
these thoughts when you're angry do this
when you're angry do that that's how you
start you need to be well you need to
want to be free from anger to begin
with and then inevit ly your
first effort will be directed at how to
manage and subdue the anger but you
mustn't confuse that for the actual
practice of the Dharma which if done
rightly will uproot the anger and then
there's nothing for you to manage no
burden for you to have to do or deal
with and if you don't do it you will
then suffer no there is nothing to be
dealt with cuz nothing affects you to
begin
with you say it's not the dummer that
management is not the dummer exactly
it's like the approximation of the
dummer but it's not it's not the it's
not the direct way one way only the way
the Buddha would describe the DH would
always only result in purification of
being like clar like um removing all the
UNH wholesomeness and making Bava cease
management doesn't do that only that
direct insight into what it what appro
suffering what is apprting the greed
what is appr rooting the aversion and
delusion so the dump so what is the Dum
what is that is a direct path to for
apprting yeah not the
management so you are kind of
responsible for whether things you're
doing whether you've taken them as
d whether you've taken them for the
purpose of uprooting the issues not
dealing with it but like making yourself
not liable to them even in the future or
have you taken the dumb instruction as
mean as a as a means sort of of helping
yourself deal with these things so it's
more like it's it's it's more it's
determined by you by your attitude
whether that instruction will be taken
as the dama or is
management that's the that's the
difference I'm pointing at you know like
you can do Sati patana which is the dama
the the the way the Buddha described but
you can do it for the reasons of
managing your suffering not for the
reasons of uprooting
it which means you are responsible for
whether it's management or it's the
dharm and yeah that's why the dhama
rises in those who
see you know I can like you can tell the
dhama directly the Buddha would teach
dhama to somebody but it wouldn't be the
Dharma for them because they're not
understanding it so there is no arising
of dhma in their
experience but he is a thing that Buddha
said but they're not understanding it so
the dhma can only arise on that
individual level
the Dum the way knowing the the
knowledge of the way the knowledge of
the way of uprooting things basically
that's what it is the knowledge of of of
overcoming liability to suffering once
and for all not just the knowledge of
how to manage it skillfully when it
arises so you can look and
see I am subject to
suffering I will things can go wrong
well exactly it's it's it's really on
that level of I will I will experience
this I am liable to this that's we often
said that that's why like we say the
wise man would reflect the young man who
leaves the home I am prayed to suffering
and not necessarily suffering now but
the suffering will catch me at some
point it's it's inevitable and you
should start you should have the like
ment basically Clarity enough mental
capacity sufficiently enough to start
seeing that as the actual root of the
problem not the fact that you might like
oh I suffer now I don't suffer tomorrow
or whatever the fact is that I will at
some point it's inevitable and that's
the true problem even if I spend the
rest of my life skillfully avoiding all
the major sufferings the fact is it will
still have to I am still liable to it I
still have to make the effort to avoid
it that's already the issue the divine
messenger you know the Buddha was
neither sick nor old nor dying when he
saw a sick aging dead
person so you see that ah this is
directly present in my experience as the
inherent liability and that's where the
issue is and that's why this this the
difference in in practice U of
management and the practice of uprooting
let's call it that way is basically in
recognizing like okay so there is no
lust in my experience here and now there
is no greed in my experience here and
now there is no delusion experience here
okay I'm fine then no but now as the
Buddha would say okay so you ask
yourself further it's good that those
things are not present here and now but
your next question should now be so is
it possible for non Arisen L to arise
later on now it's not here but can it be
here tomorrow oh have I addressed that
here and now not wait for tomorrow to
address it
and that's literally the
crossroads between are you heading in
the direction of uprooting it or are you
heading direction of management and most
people go down the path of management as
in I'll deal with it when it arises
failing to understand that liability to
Future lust is a risen issue
now you don't have to wait for it to
arise is there a chance for non-
manifested lust non- manifested aversion
to manifest in my experience
later if you're not sure means that is a
chance if you know for sure there you go
you confirm it so there is a chance that
these things will arise that's the issue
for me now when those things are not
present yeah anger is a problem
possibility for anger is a problem yeah
now not a not in the future it is now
problem and that's that's the whole
that's like the what differentiates your
practice from are you aiming at the
uprooting or are you just aiming at the
skillful management and you heard that yourself
management and you heard that yourself
before it's it's very common attitude of
oh well you know most of the time you
are not lustful most of the time you're
not angry so see you're doing fine if
most of the time you're not angry means
anger is still your liability your
possibility which means you're as as
angry like yeah you're not acting out of
that anger as often as others but that's
just cuz you learned some management of
your anger you're certainly not
uprooting anything if you have the
attitude that most of the time these
things don't arise for me yeah but could
they arise at any time yes that's the
issue you're not seeing and that's why
you're not approving
anything uh so so you see that there is
a problem because you see and know that
there is the possibility
yeah of so you have to train your mind
to start seeing these possibilities as
actually present cuz they are so you can
think to yourself I can
manage my lust or my anger quite well
I'm I'm really skilled with that I know
all these different techniques
psychological methods to employ so that
I can ease that anger ease that lust be
C again if if if your way out of
suffering is skillful managing it you
need need suffering to arise
first so management requires suffering
in order to manage it yeah so management
cannot free you from that suffering it
can only deal with it once it has arisen
and most people that's that's the kind
of problem that sort of relatively
subtle I suppose is people as I said
natural tendencies is to turn towards
management first I they get rid of the
problem do it skillfully whatever else
um but there is the this kind of
conflating that occurs then or rather
confusion so through your management of
suffering you experience like less uh
duka and uh and then at the same time
you kind of start basically tedly
assuming um hoping that all you have to
do is manage your suffering long enough
and then somehow magically liability to
dooka will
disappear so all I have to do is is is
adhere to this management and skillful
avoiding and so on and there's already
implicit as I said wishful thinking that
implies that you hope for suffering will
then just poof eventually from your
management it will just evaporate but it
won't that's the point the only way that
suffering will evaporate is if you
evaporate it if you understand the core
pull the thorn
out it won't come out by itself so
uproot
it so if you keep managing it with a
hope that somehow it will disappear on
the level of that I am still liable to
it means your practice revolves around
wishful thinking there is no direct
Insight this is what to be done for
freedom from suffering cuz yeah you
don't want everyone's goal is to not
have everybody everybody wants to to be
fully free from suffering which means
everybody wants to not even be
to discomfort and
displeasure so I start doing matter
matter matter matter matter every day
every day every day and I stay calm I
don't get
angry but I have to keep doing me
because I can so your calmness then is
dependent upon the factor of you
sustaining your effort towards whatever
you perceive met contemplation to be
which means if sometimes circumstances
change you get sick or something happens
or too many things happen you don't have
enough time so you cannot engage to that
necessary extent of your of your of your
meta contemplation means you back back
within anger so you haven't really
approved anger you just suppressed it
with with a certain
practices and as I said there is not not
it's not inherently wrong to do that to
begin with but it's inherently wrong to
adopt a view that doing that appro
things somehow magically the only way to
appro things is to directly see what Ain
is and I just described it what it is
it's recognizing that
liability the possibility of anger
possibility of ill will possibility of
sensuality possibility of delusion
possibility of duah as the duka right
now not to wait for it when it when it
occurs so you can see that possibility
see the possibility so what do you do
how do you uproot this possibility that
tomorrow you might suffer you're being
aware of that then
then
then well it's sustaining that so can
you sustain that if if you're not
keeping the precepts can you sustain
that elevated state of mind that
recognizes liability to Dua without the
actual daoka being present there if
you're drinking smoking running around
distracting yourself engaging in
entertainment no
impossible so that the noble a for path
that's how you do it right livelihood
Right View first first of all see if
your view still regards management as
the way out of
suffering you will not stay on the level
of weight it's the possibility of
suffering that's the problem there must
be dealt with not the actual suffering
when it
arises so again how do I deal with that
how do you deal with what the
possibility but Noble for path yeah so
right right view knowing that that's
where the issue is not looking elsewhere
right intentions uh not entertaining not
intentions uh not entertaining not
delighting not giving into greed
diversion delusion through your speech
through your body in your
thoughts so on every front you need to
build yourself up in order to be able to
sustain that recognition of liability
here and now it's what the issue is if
you ask yourself how do I deal with the
possibility of future suffering here and
now you're basically asking how do I
manage it how do I manage this possibility well
it how do I manage this possibility well
that's what you're implying cuz you want
to deal with it now you deal with it
properly not not give into the view of
management by realizing that you have no
right to resist it so you have to be
careful if you when you start
recognizing ah the liability of
suffering is the problem for me you have
to be careful to now not give into the
attitude of wanting to manage
that so I want it to end I want that
so I want it to end I want that
possibility to beun so then you really
have to understand where the duka is
there is the possibility in itself
duka is that possibility of future
discomfort future disagreeable things is
that in itself duka the idea yeah the
thought of it is it is it is that the
duka no so I would so what's the duka then I
no so I would so what's the duka then I
would say it's that unpleasant feeling
it's the displeasure that is that that
is there when I have that
idea right so I feel uncomfortable with
the fact that in the
future I will suffer pain which I am
suffering presently because of that but
it might be even so then the next
question you should ask yourself is the
U so the unpleasant feeling then that
you have when you think those thoughts
is that a do in itself
because it is what it is that pain well
yeah the problem is I don't want it
there so so what is then the
Dua I mean I would say okay it's the
craving to get rid of
it okay so how is that manifested what
is that practically in your experience
resistance so yeah I resist so that's
for me that sense of entitled of I I
should not have this so you
realize you suffer because you resist
the discomfort even before the
discomfort comes your way see you resist
the thought of the possibility of
discomfort here and now and that's why
here and now you experience dukka that's
why the Buddha didn't say V is the cause
of dukka he didn't say feelings are the
cause of suffering he said tanha craving
is the cause of suffering craving in
regard to what you feel so you have such
and such feeling when you have such and
such thought present future or past
but it's your implicit attitude towards
the feeling of either craving towards it
or away from it that's why that
experience is Dua and see you would have
not seen that if you haven't forced
yourself to discern the level of that
possibility of dukka is dukka right now
you wouldn't have seen that if you were
just fully bent on managing the dooka as
it arises or managing the dooka before
it arises specific pain spefic so that's
what I mean like even the even when
people recognize sometimes the future
duka liability to the Future dooka they
can they can even take that as a as
something to manage ah so I'll do this
I'll do this so these things will not
happen to me which carries the implicit
view that Dua is in those actual things
or in your actual feelings and you don't
see that it's in your attitude towards
these things and yeah it's right now
right here right now always present
exactly always experiencing that
pressure the relationship between tanha and duka
the relationship between tanha and duka
between craving and suffering it's
always present always simultaneously
present presence of suffering presence
of suffering means presence of
tan presence of tanha means presence of
suffering so to the extent that tanha is
is present to that extent suffering is
felt or to the extent the suffering is
felt to that extent attitude of tanai is
present there is no delay or like few
seconds later duka comes as a result of
your craving no presence of suffering means
craving no presence of suffering means
presence of craving presence of craving
means presence of suffering so that's
why if you were to remove the presence
of craving there is no suffering amidst
things they used to cause you to suffer
so
much if you and that's why Liberation is
visible and possible from suffering Here
and Now so that's what I mean you need
to start seeing as duah the liability to
suffering not actually wait for the
actual suffering and then manage
it cuz if you don't see that liability
then you complacent if you're not seeing
the liability means you're are not
seeing where your craving is no you're
not seeing daoka you're not seeing da
yeah you need to see the duka first in
order to see the cause of duka you can't
just be dealing with the duka without
understanding what duka is that's what
what have said I'm teaching suffering
and I'm teaching freedom from I'm
teaching only two things suffering and
freedom from it that's
it so if you don't see that possibility
of future discomfort is already Dua now
means you're not seeing the nature of
duka to begin with so doesn't matter
what happens to you you will not see it
with the correct set of eyes so to speak
MH and if you're not seeing what the daa
is here and now already you're not going
to see your craving CU I said to the
extent the dua's felt to that extent
craving is present but you're not seeing
the felt daoka thus how can you see that
which which determines it the actual
craving so that's what I mean management
looking to deal with it over there
without seeing where the actual daoka is
because you give into that need to
manage it and remove the pain as opposed
to understand it it's it's it's
inherently Bound in the wrong view it's
inherently Bound in the wrong direction
it's just like a way you could reflect
why are you entitled to to to manage
pain have you had saying it's like dwell
on the nature of that dooka even the
actual duka or the future do just just
reflecting have you heard saying it's
arising can you prevent circumstances
from becoming disagreeable at any point
in the future is that even conceivable
actually it's just a Pure Fantasy
fantasy rooted in this complete
misconceiving of the problem problem is
in these things happening to me problem
is not in me implicitly resisting the
idea of these things happening to me so
how do you stop resisting the
pain how do you then stop craving or
rather welcoming the
pleasure how do you remove craving well
we just outlined it by not trying to
manage it but by seeing it here and now
already and then by sense restraint
because you cannot possibly be welcoming
pleasure and then just dealing with the
unpleasant uh experiences when they
arise you can't just selectively pick
and choose which Cravings you
want if there is any form of craving
present means liability to suffering is
present so you have to abandon craving
for pleasure in as much you have to
abandon craving against pain yeah so
pain comes pleasure comes you you have
no saying it's
arising so why do you then
constantly um entertain the attitude of
I want this I don't want this I have
right to want this I have right to not
want this why do you go after one try to
this why do you go after one try to
avoid the other one where is your
attitude rooted why are you doing
it cuz it's because Pleasure and Pain is
yeah it's felt it's a pressure it's
prees you you feel the so it's painful
to not do it yeah so you do it cuz you
want to avoid pain cuz it's pressuring
that pain is pain is pressuring so
exactly so you don't know how to deal
with duka thus you try to get rid of
duka that's basically the the the the
the nutshell of every management and
that's why say it's inherently wrong
even if you're doing the dharm all the
Buddha's instruction but you're taking
them as management means you still
entertain the same attitude because of
which you suffer suffer in the first
place which is I can handle this I want
to get rid of it which is the attitude
of
craving so how can you then withstand
the pressure how can you withstand the
pressure that's but withstanding the pressure
that's but withstanding the pressure
yeah but can you withstand the pressure
if even your physical behavior is not
kept in check can you withstand mental
pressure then
impossible if your verbal Behavior
behavior is not kept in check like the
outpour of lust and anger through your
physical action through your verbal
action if you don't keep LD on that can
you possibly withstand things mentally
not a chance and how do you do that by
doing it like how do you become stronger
well by exposing yourself to things that
will make you stronger by
training I said it many times like even
when I first read I suas I was bit
puzzled but keeps kept talking about he
trains himself thus a mon skill trains
himself does cuz you know you had all
these Notions about Enlightenment and so
it's like what is there to train you
know you do things and then
Enlightenment happens to you no you
train the strength out of which wisdom
comes which is what enlightenment
is so that's why sense restraint is not
optional that's what virtue is not you
know oh I can do it for a while it's a
necessary basis that has to remain
throughout so you will be able to
withstand the pressure by not giving
into
pressure by not giving into pressure you
get to outline what the actual problem
is your liability to Future pressure to
Future discomfort is already problem
right here right
now and you see that now because you
haven't just blindly gave in to managing
of the pressure in order to get rid of
the pressure manage the stress in order to
pressure manage the stress in order to
get rid of the stress practice the
Dharma so you don't get this particular
stress anymore
I recognize that there's a possibility
of
suffering and I see that suffering right
now it's suffering because I resist the
displeasure here and now in regard to
the
possibility it's suffering because I
resist so I
don't resisted that discomfort Here and Now
resisted that discomfort Here and Now
mhm but I must have that must still have
the idea
that I don't have to keep on thinking
about that there's a possibility of me
suffering tomorrow no that will come and
go so whatever basically I have to look
at whatever I'm feeling right now yeah
yeah cuz that's where the resistance
occurs that's where craving is it's
where you feel yeah I can put the the
possibility of suffing I can put that
aside because now I know what the
problem is here and now sure sure so
I've I've come to that you start you
contemplate the possibility of suffering
when you forget what the problem is here
and now or you're not seeing it well you
could yeah like sadik Puta used to ask
himself I think it was
sadika what am I liable to anything to
any suffering is something that yeah it
was something like is there any
suffering that can arise in yeah is
there any any suffering that hasn't that
the possibility of suffering hasn't been
like addressed so to speak yeah and like
no I don't see any okay
he still doesn't decide okay I'm done
now no you remain with that Vigilant
attitude you don't okay I'll check I'll
check in every now and then and see if
something has changed if possibility for
lust aversion delusion possibility for
pressure possibility for Central Pool
possibility for suffering has that
Arisen now not the actual suffering but
the possibility for it being oh look
yeah now I see yeah it could it's
possible there you go that's your issue
right there and then
so what you do well you don't lose the
sight of it to begin with that feeling
yeah you don't welcome it if it's the
possibility to its pleasure and
sensuality and you don't resist it if
it's the possibility towards pain and
and
discomfort is there anything that is
there a possibility for me uh indulging
in welcoming indulging is too course
already it's the result of pleasure in
the future exactly so it's on the level
of the possibility of pleasure or
possibility of pain which means it's on
the level of welcoming or kind of shying
away from it's atler so think if someone
brings me a pizza tomorrow I love the
taste of pizza will I will I welcome
that pleasure pleasurable taste will I
get lost and you will you will know that
if you're looking at things rightly you
will know that already now you'll know
oh oh I can't wait even if you are
perfectly restrained and don't express
your joy over the particular type of
food brought to you you already
internally you know what it what it is
and so that and that's the problem and
but there's the work and that's the work
exactly that's where the issue
is and people would okay so I will tell
them never to bring that thing again cuz
I like it too much it's like well you
can do that as a way of like if you
really can't deal with things so okay
put it aside but that's really masking
the issue the issue is not the pizza
whatever people have brought to you the
issue is you're unable to restrain
yourself you're unable to have mind free
from greed so now you're just trying to
remove things that make you greedy but
you're unable to not
be wanting pleasure you are unable to
exact to to to to not welcome that
pressure of that pleasure you're unable
which means that's why you will remain
liable you can spend 100 Years of that
management you will never appro your
sensuality so you feel the pressure of
pain that resistance against it
and you stop well exactly you don't try
to get rid of
it you don't try to psychologize manage
explain prevent things from arising
obviously if something obviously UNH
wholesome like like like when that man
came and offered wanted to offer his
daughter to the Buddha and was said no
don't even bother I will not accept that
yeah like certain things cannot be done
rightly such as sexual intercourse and
and so on but there are things that
there's nothing like there's nothing
wrong in eating food whether it's tasty
or
not but it's wrong in eating it with
sensual reasons and you
eat and you eat the you eat your food
with sentual reasons when where you are
unable to to not be overwhelmed by that
uh pressure towards accepting
pleasure so that's what would would say
like when you when you practice in
regard to the food you not like you stop
eating no you eat mindfully you maintain the
no you eat mindfully you maintain the
reasons for your eating clearly and you
eat while those reasons are present
reasons for health sustaining the body
so that you can practice further not
reasons of beautifications Chasing The
Taste and so on but if you just think if
I avoid the food I don't have to deal
with these reasons well you're solely
mistaken you're just covering up the
basis of your
sensuality so even if you just eat
horrible stuff all the time because you
don't want to experience experience any
sensal joy of the taste you still need
to look at these reasons and keep the
Vigilant eye on them because that's
where sensuality is
rooted not in the actual
taste so am I welcoming am I delighting
am I accepting this Elation on account
of central prospect that is pleasing to
me that's the issue my acceptance not
seeing the danger in it not the maintain
main not that's the issue not the issue
is oh I must not have this thing arise
for me at
all so call people tell them never to
bring their food never you'll never see
anything you'll never hear anything
you'll never taste anything
agreeable me you you're not you're
misconceiving where the issue is yeah
and you're maintaining the issue well
you remain fully within it yeah that's
why you you're not you're not stepping
outside of central domain there might be
someone that comes along and that's why
the aism the atmos form like you know
Giants you know the the perfect practice
of of of obsessive hinga nonviolence not
eating not harming anything it's AR
misguided CU it's fully
mispred they don't see where the issue
really is you know avoiding food any and
just eating every third day or something
to the point of in the end you die on
account of starvation and that's like
the ultimate goal of a GI yet you
realize you fully remain Bound by the
central domain never a step closer to
escape it
it was the the James that said that by
avoiding things then you you you
diminish them you diminish the pressure
but where is the Buddhist
ways well because it's not always the
same things you don't always have one
attitude towards all things if you were
to only have the attitude of accepting
everything every type of feeling every
type of perception then Giants would
have been right all you need to do is
avoid it cuz you always accept it but
but that's not the case you're not
you're not accepting the the
unpleasurable feelings you are actually
trying to get rid of them you're only
accepting certain things but then you're
resisting some other things and so it's
not a blanket rule always avoid because
it's not a blanket experience that
that's always the
same that's why what you do whether you
avoid or whether you have to basically
endure is determined by how you feel and
you don't even feel the always the same
in regard to the same things sometimes
one same food might make you happy
sometimes might make you unpleasant
sometimes might might make you
indifferent which means you have three
different types of feel you have three
different types of
attitude that will then exhibit the
craving but if you always avoid
everything you're ignoring 2third of
that picture and that's why you will
remain ignorant MH
so how can you then know when to reject
and when to accept like when you're
resisting gratuitously the future
Prospect of
suffering should you be rejecting that
even more no you need to accept that
these possibilities are there present
and you have no say in it that's how you
can then stop resisting it gratuitously
and thus you approve the
suffering or should you then accept the
the Prospect of future pleasure that you
already delighted in no you must reject
that you must contemplate the danger in
it so how do you know what you do well
by learning how to be properly mindful
of an enduring feeling because that's
where things converge that's where
things are
rooted you can't just set take a set of
behavior that I always do this when it's
this and this when it's that no first
you just need to remain mindful of
what's the present enduring feeling and
you will know then what attitude is
there if the pleasant enduring feeling
is of pleasure and agreeability means
you have the attitude of welcoming it by
default but you must so that's that's
what you reject you reject your
welcoming of this Central pleasure you
don't blame like giants the actual
object of your central
pleasure so you will know what attitude
is
there by correctly understanding what
present feeling is
there that's the root of the problem
there's the the it's always present the
root of the problem is always present
it's not in the past it will not be in
the future that's the root of the
problem that attitude exactly and the
root of that present route is basically
your attitude towards the present
enduring feeling so it's whatever
suffering will arise in the future is
always that's the gayway it's within
that that doesn't disappear when the
suffering arrived that remains its
vessel so to speak its framework as I
say because no matter of future
discomfort and suffering can affect you
unless you're holding on to that vessel
of rejecting it like the vessel of
rejection basically of any discomfort
that's your
mindset so anything that comes of
discomfortable nature is going to make
you suffer because of your attitude of
not wanting it you remove the attitude
of that cud is at of not wanting the
discomfort not necessarily seeking it
out but certainly not trying to get rid
of it when when it's there exactly when
it's circumstantially arise which
inevitably will ah then you're not
cultiv in that gratuitous mindset of of
resistance which means your craving is
now truly
diminishing and
same you will diminish your craving when
you don't cultivate Gru's mindset of
welcoming as the what would say
delighting entertaining the Notions of
current and future
pleasure like why you like when you ask
yourself am I liable to Future cenal
desire oh yes why because here and now
I'm still holding it there I'm still
welcoming coming the prospect of it here
and now I haven't approved it not I
haven't dealt with it rightly once it
has arisen no it's on the level of that
possible future sensuality is only
possible because right here right now I
am still valuing it I'm still haven't
seen the thorough danger in it I'm still
on some level delighting in it and that
Delight is to be dealt with Here and Now
not in the future when that thing arises